[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "The crafts that are created using fire are called as:",
    "options": [
      "Pyrotechnology",
      "Non- Pyrotechnology",
      "Metallurgy",
      "Thermal Technology"
    ],
    "answer": "Pyrotechnology"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "The Key Concepts in Upanishads include:",
    "options": [
      "Brahman, Maya, Karma and Reincarnation, Moksha",
      "Brahman, Atman, Maya, Karma and Reincarnation, Moksha",
      "Brahman, Atman, Karma and Reincarnation, Moksha",
      "Brahman, Atman, Maya, Karma and Reincarnation"
    ],
    "answer": "Brahman, Atman, Maya, Karma and Reincarnation, Moksha"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "The CORRECT sequence of Harappan Civilization is:",
    "options": [
      "Decline and Transformation; Formative; Urbanization and Peak.",
      "Formative; Urbanization and Peak; Decline and Transformation.",
      "Urbanization and Peak; Formative; Decline and Transformation.",
      "Decline and Transformation; Urbanization and Peak; Formative."
    ],
    "answer": "Formative; Urbanization and Peak; Decline and Transformation."
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Match the Yuga:",
    "options": [
      "1-iii; 2-ii; 3-iv; 4-i",
      "1-ii; 2-i; 3-iii; 4-iv",
      "1-i; 2-ii; 3-iii; 4-iv",
      "1-iv; 2-i; 3-iii; 4-ii"
    ],
    "answer": "1-iii; 2-ii; 3-iv; 4-i"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Indian civilization uniquely integrates:",
    "options": [
      "linear perceptions only",
      "cyclic perceptions only",
      "both cyclic and linear perceptions of time",
      "non Linear"
    ],
    "answer": "both cyclic and linear perceptions of time"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "The passes in Northern Mountain Passes",
    "options": [
      "The passes in Northern Mountain Passes",
      "Khyser pass, Goomali pass, Boolean pass",
      "Khymer pass, Golam pass, Google pass",
      "Bolan pass, Khyber pass, Gomal pass"
    ],
    "answer": "Bolan pass, Khyber pass, Gomal pass"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "The Indo-Gangetic Plain contains:",
    "options": [
      "The perennial supply of water to the rivers primarily comes from glaciers in the northern mountains.",
      "The perennial supply of water to the rivers primarily comes from valley in the northern mountains.",
      "The perennial supply of water to the rivers primarily comes from deserts in the northern mountains.",
      "The perennial supply of water to the rivers primarily comes from plains in the northern mountains."
    ],
    "answer": "The perennial supply of water to the rivers primarily comes from glaciers in the northern mountains."
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "The periods in IKS History are:",
    "options": [
      "Vedic Period, Upanishadic Period, Classical Period only",
      "Vedic Period, Upanishadic Period, Classical Period, Medieval Period, Colonial Period, Post-Independence Era",
      "Classical Period, Medieval Period, Colonial Period only",
      "Vedic Period, Upanishadic Period, Classical Period, Medieval Period, Colonial Period only"
    ],
    "answer": "Vedic Period, Upanishadic Period, Classical Period, Medieval Period, Colonial Period, Post-Independence Era"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "The Vedas are divided into four main texts:",
    "options": [
      "Rup Veda, Soma Veda, Yamar Veda, Atharva Veda",
      "Rog Veda, Soma Veda, Yamar Veda, Atharva Veda",
      "Rk Veda, Sama Veda, Yajur Veda, Atharva Veda",
      "Soma Veda, Yamar Veda, Atharva Veda"
    ],
    "answer": "Rk Veda, Sama Veda, Yajur Veda, Atharva Veda"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Varna system comprised of",
    "options": [
      "Pirots, warriors, merchants/farmers, and labourers.",
      "Priests, warriors, non-productive, and labourers.",
      "Priests, wisers , merchants/farmers, and labourers.",
      "Priests , warriors, merchants/farmers, and labourers."
    ],
    "answer": "Priests , warriors, merchants/farmers, and labourers."
  }
]